<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><Search><pages Count="16"><page Index="1" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Effective Comprehensive Authentic
      A Spanish reading program for teaching reading, spelling, and handwriting
1
 ]]></page><page Index="2" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Research
In 2019, Yale University and Universidad Favaloro conducted a research study in schools in the province of Buenos Aires. The project compared classes that implemented Aprendo Leyendo with others that continued their usual teaching method. The results were statistically significant: Aprendo Leyendo students had better results at the sentence
level in the reading comprehension test.
To read the complete report, visit: http://www.intelexia.com/investigacion-2019
 What are teachers saying?
“My 1° grade students started to read aloud from the beginning of the course and by the end of the year were able to read one whole book by themselves. Witnessing the progress of their literary skills is amazing, especially their motivation, their willingness to read aloud in each class with no fear of making mistakes, their enthusiasm for ongoing learning. As a teacher, it is exciting to be part of this. Listening to them read and watching them smile is a gift in every reading class!”
Sofía, 1st grade reading teacher
 2
      ]]></page><page Index="3" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ For Teachers, By Teachers Effective
Aprendo Leyendo is a beginning reading program that incorporates reading, spelling, and handwriting using multisensory techniques. It utilizes the best instructional practices supported by scientific research and is an effective program for all children.
Comprehensive
Aprendo Leyendo contains all the critical elements of a comprehensive reading program for primary grades: phonemic awareness, phonics, decoding, word recognition, vocabulary, spelling, handwriting, and comprehension strategies. All these vital components of reading are taught simultaneously in integrated lessons, each subject reinforcing and strengthening the others.
Authentic
Aprendo Leyendo was written by Latin American authors. All the stories are authentic and relevant to the culture and people of the continent. In addition, the teacher instructions are concise and easily accessible. There is no need for a large assortment of books and materials for each area of study. Everything children need for a lesson is contained in just two books: a decodable chapter book and a Skills Book.
   1
]]></page><page Index="4" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Chapter Books
For Students
These beautifully illustrated decodable chapter books are unlike any other beginning readers. The narratives have all the basic elements of good storytelling—character, setting, plot, conflict, and resolution. Children love the adventure and humor!
The decodable text only contains sounds that have been taught so that children can sound out the words. There is a repetition of vocabulary to develop recognition of common words and the length of words and complexity of sentences gradually increases. The books provide the practice needed to develop accurate and fluent reading, as well as coherent stories that support effective comprehension strategies.
Skills Books
Each chapter book has a corresponding Skills Book. Comprehensive Skills Books contain activities for teachers to provide direct instruction in phonemic awareness, decoding, word recognition, spelling, handwriting, vocabulary, and comprehension. They are meant to be used under teacher supervision with discussion and immediate feedback.
       2
]]></page><page Index="5" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[Teacher Editions
For Teachers
Each chapter book also has a Teacher Edition that provides prompts to support children’s engagement and understanding of the stories. The resulting class discussions encourage logical reasoning, making inferences, and a range of comprehension strategies, including rereading, paraphrasing, and summarizing.
Aprendo Leyendo Teacher Handbook
The Teacher Handbook includes detailed instructions on how to implement the program, as well as words and sentences for spelling dictations for each level of the AL sequence.
Professional Development
Professional Development, in the form of courses, workshops, and ongoing teacher support, is provided by experienced AL teachers and can be tailored to the needs of individual schools and districts.
Online Resources
Curriculum-based Tests Placement Tests Lesson Plan Forms
Supplementary Materials
Alphabet Picture Cards Pocket Chart Alphabet Cards Review Packs
Reinforcement Activities Homework
     3
]]></page><page Index="6" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[How the materials are used in a typical lesson.
Level 23 v (vaca)
    Dictado Si bien en este Paso los niños empiezan a leer signos de pregunta, no deben ser incluidos en los Dictados hasta el Paso 71. En este Paso el maestro dicta y repasa aquellos sonidos, sílabas, palabras o frases con los que los niños hayan tenido dificultad.
Lectura Cuentos En Casa, Paso 22 “En cama” Es importante prestar atención a todos los signos de puntuación que van apareciendo: puntos finales, comas, signos de interrogación y de exclamación. El autor los puso con una intención. Si es necesario, el maestro modela la correcta entonación en cada caso. Otras actividades Página 38. Intruso Página 39. Escritura Los sustantivos propios Mate y Pepe empiezan con mayúscula. Página 40. Comprensión Primero los niños leen en voz alta las oraciones, luego ilus- tran según corresponda. Descargar las páginas de Tarea de la plataforma digital Tarea o práctica adicional Aprendo Leyendo. pág. 39. Escritura Letra v 23 paso Repaso Las tarjetas del Cuadernillo 1 que presenten dificultad Cuadernillo 2: e Palabras con Prisa: no, lago, ella, está, con, contenta Introducción de Material Nuevo: v - Es el sonido /b/, como al comienzo de la palabra “vaca” - En este Paso, cuando se habla del sonido /b/, siempre es el de la letra v corta, la de vaca.
104 ©2017 intelexia.com
      Plan the Lesson
1
Review
2
Introduction of New Material
Plan the lesson
using the Teacher Handbook and the Teacher Edition.
Review previously taught sounds and nonphonetic words, using the Review Pack.
Introduce the new phonogram, using the keyword card from the Alphabet Picture Cards and Skills Book pages.
                    4
]]></page><page Index="7" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   3
Spelling Dictation
4
Reading
Give a dictation with the new phonogram, using words and a sentence provided in the Teacher Handbook.
Read a list of words
with children from the Skills Books to develop decoding skills, word recognition, and reading fluency.
Read a chapter
with children
in the En Casa reader to develop comprehension strategies.
                5
Reinforcement
Provide reinforcement activities from the Skills Book.
5
]]></page><page Index="8" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   Paso a paso
• Consonants: 9 Vowels: 1
• Phonemic awareness
• vcv words (for example, casa)
• Introduction of proper and common nouns • Use of tilde
• Sentences: basic punctuation
• Multiple-meaning words
        Handwriting
Phonemic Awareness
    Phonics
 6
Sentence Comprehension
Accuracy and Fluency
Levels 1 - 16
 ]]></page><page Index="9" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[             Multiple-meaning Words
En casa
• Consonants: 14 Vowels: 2
• vcv words with three syllables
• Pronouns
• Suffix -s (plural)
• Introduction of interrogative
and exclamatory sentences
• Articles and nouns
• Stories: reading comprehension
strategies
Story Comprehension
        Accuracy and Fluency
Chapter Book
Levels 17 - 32
7
 ]]></page><page Index="10" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[      • • • •
• • • •
A la playa
Consonants: 18. Vowels: 3
vccv words
Infinitive and third person plural Conjunctions: comprehension and use of pero, por eso, and porque Idioms
Articles
Synonyms and antonyms Stories: reading comprehension strategies
Story Comprehension
    Palabras con Prisa
Accuracy and Fluency
      8
Phrase Comprehension
Chapter Book
Levels 33 - 46
  ]]></page><page Index="11" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[         Following Directions
Spelling
Accuracy and Fluency
En la escuela
• Complete alphabet
• Expository text
• Sufffix -es (plural)
• Suffixes -ito/ita
• Verbs: simple present tense
• Sentence writing
• Stories: reading comprehension
strategies
          Sentence Comprehension
Story Comprehension
Chapter Book
Levels 47 - 64
 9
 ]]></page><page Index="12" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[       • • • • • • • • •
A la ciudad
vv words (for example, después) Consonant clusters
Vowel combinations
Letter c /s/ and letter g /j / Question marks
Verbs: past, present, and future tense Problem solving
Cardinal and ordinal numbers
Stories: reading comprehension strategies
Syllable Division
    Verbs
     10
Story Comprehension
Chapter Book
Levels 65 - 80
  ]]></page><page Index="13" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[          Nonfiction Text
Text Comprehension
Al más allá
• vcccv words
• Suffixes
• Pronominal verbs
• Digraph gu + e, i
• Conjugations: -amos/emos/imos,
-aron/ieron, -ando/iendo
• Stories: reading comprehension strategies
Reading Comprehension
       Suffixes
Compound words
Chapter Book
11
Levels 81 - 96
  ]]></page><page Index="14" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Teacher Materials
Cards
Teacher Edition
       Teacher Handbook
+ +
+ +
+ +
            +
       Dictado
en los Dictados hasta el Paso 71.
Si bien en este Paso los niños empiezan a leer signos de pregunta, no deben ser incluidos que los niños hayan tenido dificultad.
En este Paso el maestro dicta y repasa aquellos sonidos, sílabas, palabras o frases con los
Lectura
Cuentos En Casa, Paso 22 “En cama”
una intención. Si es necesario, el maestro modela la correcta entonación en cada caso. puntos finales, comas, signos de interrogación y de exclamación. El autor los puso con Es importante prestar atención a todos los signos de puntuación que van apareciendo:
  Otras actividades
Página 38. Intruso
Página 39. Escritura
mayúscula.
Los sustantivos propios Mate y Pepe empiezan con
Página 40. Comprensión
tran según corresponda.
Primero los niños leen en voz alta las oraciones, luego ilus-
Aprendo Leyendo.
Descargar las páginas de Tarea de la plataforma digital Tarea o práctica adicional
pág. 39. Escritura
 Letra v 23 paso
Repaso
Cuadernillo 2: e
Las tarjetas del Cuadernillo 1 que presenten dificultad
Palabras con Prisa: no, lago, ella, está, con, contenta
Introducción de Material Nuevo: v
- En este Paso, cuando se habla del sonido /b/, siempre es el de la letra v corta, la de v - Es el sonido /b/, como al comienzo de la palabra “vaca”
104 ©2017 intelexia.com
                  aca.
 Páginas 41 y 45. Conciencia fonológica
Dictado
Páginas 42 y 43. Grafía Grande y Grafía Pequeña
En este Dictado siempre se escribe la letra v cuando se escucha
el sonido /b/.
Sílabas: va, ve
Palabras cortitas: va, ve, van, ven, vas, ves
Opciones:
Él vale la pena. Papá ve al ave. Pepe va a la mesa.
Palabras: cava, vale, nave, ave, vaca, pava, vela
Oraciones: Papá lava esa pava. Pepe ama esa ave.
Conciencia fonológica
pág. 41.
  Lectura
Palabras y oraciones. Cazar Palabras: un animal, algo para calentar agua, algo que
ilumina.
Página 44. Lista
Palabras Cortitas y oraciones.
Página 46. Lista
IMPORTANTE
Recordar que las Listas de palabras están pensadas para leerlas una y otra vez como
práctica de Lectura en voz alta.
 Otras actividades
Cuentos En Casa, Paso 23 “En el lago”
Se aclara que todos los personajes están en los marcos de fo-
tos porque son personajes de los Cuentos. Como sustantivos
Página 47. Escritura y Comprensión
propios, sus nombres llevan siempre mayúscula. Los niños
leen las oraciones y escriben el nombre del personaje al cual
se refieren. Se leen las oraciones varias veces.
Descargar las páginas de Tarea de la plataforma digital
Aprendo Leyendo.
Tarea o práctica adicional
pág. 47. Escritura
  ©2017 intelexia.com 105
          12
    ]]></page><page Index="15" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[ Student Materials
Skills Book and Reader Level
  Levels 1 - 16
      Levels 17 - 32
     Levels 33 - 46
    Levels 47 - 64
     Levels 65 - 80
     Levels 81 - 96
13
      ]]></page><page Index="16" isMAC="true"><![CDATA[   14
For more information, please contact:
info@intelexia.com
To view sample materials, visit:
http://www.intelexia.com/productos
FOLLOW US:
@intelexia
Intelexia - AprendoLeyendo
 ]]></page></pages></Search>